michaeljfox.org 2017-02-03

# The Michael J. Fox Foundation Privacy Policy | Parkinson's Disease

The Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson's Research is committed to safeguarding your privacy. This statement explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way the information you provide us is collected and used. For easy and direct access, we provide a link to this statement from our home page and all other pages of the site. The Foundation is the sole owner of and the only organization that uses the personal information collected on this site. We will not sell or rent this information to others under any circumstances. This Privacy Policy applies to all information received by the Foundation, both online and offline, as well as any electronic, written or oral communication.

**"Cookies"**   
This site uses cookies. By using this site, you agree that the Foundation may place cookies on your device and access them when you visit our site. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we put on your computer. The cookies we use aid us in improving our site and your experience by tracking which areas and features of our site are popular, making the site easier to navigate, count visits, and allow a registered user to remain signed in to his/her user profile throughout a visit. We may also use cookies placed on our site by third parties acting on our behalf. If you want to opt out of our cookies, you can delete them and any other cookies that are already on your computer. Please refer to the help and support areas on your Internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. Some functionalities on our site may be affected if you delete our cookies.

**Online Donations**   
The Foundation collects the following information through our secure online financial-transaction pages: name, address, e-mail address, phone number, and credit card information. This personally identifiable information is used to acknowledge receipt of your donation for tax purposes and to include you on the Foundation's mailing list if you choose to join it.

When you send a donation in honor or in memory of someone and request that an acknowledgement be sent to another individual or a family, we will use the name and address of that individual or family for acknowledgement purposes only.

**Security**   
We care about the security of your transactions and apply industry-standard practices and technologies to safeguard your credit card information. We use high-grade encryption and the secure https protocol to communicate with your browser software, which guards against interception of the credit card information you give us. We also employ several different security techniques to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the organization. The Web servers for the Foundation are located in a locked, secure environment, and computer systems are maintained in accordance with industry standards to secure information.You should be aware, however, that "perfect security" does not exist on the Internet, and third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications.

**Mailing List**   
The Foundation provides a separate online form to join our mailing list. The information we collect includes: name, address, e-mail address, and phone number. This information is securely stored internally and accessed only when we correspond with our mailing list periodically during the year, either via e-mail or regular mail.

Please contact us directly by regular mail if at any time you wish to be removed from the mailing list or if you would like to correct or change the personal information you have previously provided. To protect your privacy and security, we will take certain steps to verify your identity before granting access to your information or making corrections. Callers will be asked specific questions, including full name, address, phone number, and, if applicable, credit card numbers and/or expiration date, in order to verify their identity and protect the privacy of the Foundation's donors and members of its mailing list.

**eNewsletters**   
You will be added to The Michael J. Fox Foundation's email newsletter list only if you register to receive newsletters via a form or checkbox on The Michael J. Fox Foundation website. You may opt out of receiving our eNewsletters by clicking on the opt-out link included in every email newsletter we send.

**Links to Other Web Sites**   
The Foundation's site includes links, some temporary and some permanent, to other Web sites. We are not responsible for the privacy and security practices of any other Web site or the nature of the content contained therein.

**Children's Privacy**   
None of the content and information in the Foundation's Web site is targeted toward children under 13 years of age. We make every effort possible to ensure that we do not collect or maintain information on our Web site from those we know to be younger than 16 unless parental consent has been obtained in writing.

**Changes to This Policy**   
In the event that the Foundation decides to alter its privacy policy, the changes will be added directly to this statement. We will, however, always use information in accordance with the version of the privacy policy under which it was originally collected.

**Contact Us**   
If you have specific questions or concerns about the Foundation's privacy policy, please contact us at the following address:

The Michael J. Fox Foundation for Parkinson's Research   
Grand Central Station  
P.O. Box 4777  
New York, NY 10163-4777
